准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
蟹堡乐园
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
不知道你是怎么做出来的  小蜗
I don't know how you do it, Gar Bear
那是我喝过最棒的一杯法式吐司
But that's the best cup of French toast I've ever had
该去上班打卡了
Well, time to punch that clock
不过上班前得先看看
But not before checking
我的每日激励鸡汤日历
my motivational quote-a-day calendar
你是大赢家
6月21日  夏天的第一天
"You are a winner"
今天还是夏天的第一天
And today's the first day of summer
夏天的第一天快乐  章鱼哥
Happy first day of summer, Squidward
要不要一起来唱夏至颂歌
Care to join me for solstice caroling?
走在草地上  真晴朗
Walking in the grass, it's all fine
夏天里来不用穿鞋子
Don't need shoes in the summertime
我可不怎么喜欢夏天  海绵宝宝
I'm not much of a summer person, SpongeBob
我的老天啊
Davy Jones on the jib
我没听错吧
Do my ears deceive me?
今天真是夏天的第一天吗
Is it really the first day of summer?
是吗
Is it?
是啊
Yeah
蟹老板  你肯定患上了
Gee, Mr. K, you sure have
很严重的夏天热
a scorching case of summer fever
夏日究竟有何物
What is it about summertime
能让我们如此开心呢
that makes us so happy?
是萤火虫点亮的夜晚
The firefly-lit nights?
还是木炭煤球醉人的芳香
The intoxicating aroma of a charcoal briquette?
还是割草机碾上拖鞋的助眠声响呢
The hypnotic sound of a lawn mower
running over a flip-flop?
是钱
The money
钱
The money?
我是说
I mean, uh
小孩子
the children
知道吗  小子
You see, boy
夏天的时候
during the summer
小孩子都不用上课了
the children are excused from their classes
这段休息的时间通常被称作暑假
A recess commonly referred to as summer break
多告诉我点暑假的事吧
Tell me more about summer break
裤头村学校
暑假的时候
Well, during the summer break
小孩子就会没人管  到裤头村到处逛
the children wander Bikini Bottom unsupervised
而且口袋里装满了零花钱
their pockets lined with allowance
爱怎么花就怎么花
free to spend their money
家长什么的根本管不着
without any parental guidance whatsoever
儿童餐
那种事情我最喜欢了
I guess that's what I like best
不过肯定会有谁会想
Sure I suppose some would try
借此机会大捞一笔
and take advantage of this situation
给他们兜售玩具或者糖果
by selling them toys or candy
但是有这么一件事  能让我高枕无忧
But I sleep well at night with the knowledge
那就是我可以给小孩子提供必需品
that I'm providing them with something they need
营养大餐
A nutritious meal
快过来  你们这些小猪崽子
Come here, you little piggies
我学到夏天的真谛了
I've been taught the true meaning of summer
之后
就快关门了  蟹老板
Almost closing time, Mr. K
什么
What?
可是不可能啊
But that's impossible
钱可怎么办
What about the money?
我是说
I mean, uh
小孩子怎么办
What about the children?
看来今年夏天来不了了
I guess summer isn't coming this year
小朋友应该都在那边新修的游乐场里
Maybe they're all at that new playground over there
游乐场
Playground?
把我的小客人们都给引走了
Luring away me young customers?
发动汽船  海绵宝宝
Warm up the boat, SpongeBob
看见什么了吗  蟹老板
See anything, Mr. Krabs?
他们就在这
They're here all right
看看他们  海绵宝宝
Just look at them, SpongeBob
多么脆弱  多么营养不良
So weak and malnourished
还没人给他们卖东西
with nobody trying to sell them nothing
太伤我心了
Breaks me heart
不行
No
我生活都失去目的了  海绵宝宝
I got nothing to live for, SpongeBob
你都能一边开船
The way you drove the boat
一边躺地上了  还算是有点酷的了
while lying on the ground was kind of cool
确实
True
可那样还是没法让这些小屁孩
But that's not going to get these munchkins
离开这游乐场
away from this playground
除非
Unless
明天见  小子
See you tomorrow, boy
得去干一堆活呢
Got a lot of work to do
没问题  蟹老板
You got it, Mr. Krabs
新的一天也要赚钱
Another day, another dollar
不知蟹老板干了啥活  自上次见到他
Gee, I wonder what Mr. Krabs has been up to
since I saw him last
过后我就回家无所事事
and then went home
to do nothing of particular interest
一直到现在
till this very moment
蟹堡乐园  欢腾一夏
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你来得正好  现在要来盛大揭幕
You're just in time for the grand unveiling of
蟹堡乐园
Krabby Land
蟹堡乐园吗  老板
Krabby Land, sir?
对  蟹堡乐园
Yes, Krabby Land
蟹堡乐园
小孩子可以在这大玩特玩
Where a kid can have fun
而且价格公道
For the right price
欢迎光临蟹堡王  小朋友
Welcome to the Krusty Krab, young man
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
梦露
Monroe
很高兴认识你  梦露
Nice to meet you, Monroe
好了  钱
Okay, Money
我是说
I mean, uh
小孩子
children
是时候盛大揭幕钱了
It's time for the grand unveiling of Money
我是说  蟹堡乐园
I mean, Krabby Land
小朋友们  现在跟蟹叔叔保证
Okay, kids, now promise Uncle Krabs
要是你们玩的时候饿了
that if you get hungry while you're playing
你们就进蟹堡王里面买既美味
you'll come inside for some delicious
又营养的蟹黄堡
nutritious Krabby Patties
我们保证
We promise
那好  揭幕了
All right, here we go
为大家献上
I give you
蟹堡乐园
Krabby Land
欢乐
堡垒探险
水管世界
面包机马术
梦幻火箭船
我在哪
Where am I?
我想起来了
That reminds me
忘了给你们这些涂色书
I forgot to give you these coloring books
兼免责条款了
slash liability waivers
只要交回来
Everyone who hands theirs back
就可以看到独一无二的蟹堡堡小丑
gets to meet the one and only Krabby the Clown
好好去玩吧
Have fun
也别忘了去吃超多
And don't forget to eat plenty
富含维生素的蟹黄堡
of vitamin-enriched Krabby Patties
蟹堡堡小丑最爱吃这个了
Krabby the Clown's favorite meal
我们要蟹堡堡
We want Krabby
蟹堡堡在哪  蟹老板
Where is Krabby, Mr. Krabs?
我数完他们钱了他才会来
He'll be here after I count their money
拖住他们就好
Just stall them
拖住他们
Stall them?
怎么个拖法
How do I do that?
不知道  陪他们玩
I don't know, be entertaining
小朋友们
Hey, kids
你不是蟹堡堡小丑
You're not Krabby the Clown
我确实不是
No, I'm not
我是
I'm, uh
我是蟹堡堡心爱的小跟班
I'm Krabby's beloved sidekick
蟹黄堡
the Krabby Patty
大盗
Burglar
垃圾
Lame
蟹堡堡马上就会到的
Krabby will be here soon
他
He, uh
得搭公交来
had to take the bus
不过这个时候呢  一起来玩吧
But in the meantime, let's have some fun
你们喜欢泡泡吗
You kids like bubbles?
不喜欢
No
那是因为你们没见过我吹的泡泡
Well, you've never seen my bubbles
快看
Voila
水母形状的泡泡
A bubble shaped like a jellyfish
怎么样呢
How about that?
还是垃圾
Still lame
那好吧
Okay
准备好大吃一惊吧
Prepare to be blown back on your tail fins
哒哒
Ta-dah
你太垃圾了
You stink
快带小丑来
Bring on the clown
好吧
Okay
现在是压轴好戏
Now for a finale
我的眼睛
My eyes
末日坑
海草圈秋千
他们貌似对我痛苦有反应
They seem to respond to me being in pain
他们喜欢别人受苦
They enjoy other people's misery
小朋友们
Hey, kids
快看这个
Check this out
终于把他们控制住了
I've got them right where I want them
利马豆
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
我再也拖不下去了
I can't take much more of this stalling stuff
你老是就只想着你自己
Always thinking about yourself
快出去拖
Get out there and stall
你胳膊跟腿怎么了  小子
What happened to your arms and legs, boy?
小孩子拿它们当回旋镖来玩
The kids are using them as boomerangs
回旋镖
Boomerangs?
不好
Oh, no
我窗户会被砸坏的
They might break my windows
要怎么办
What are we going to do?
那既然小孩的钱都数完了
Well, now that all their money's counted
就去说蟹堡堡到了
tell them Krabby has just arrived
真的吗
Really?
他到了
He's here?
好耶好耶
Oh, boy, oh, boy
快出去跟他们讲
Get out there and tell them
大家听一下
Listen, everybody
蟹堡堡小丑已经来店里了
Krabby the Clown is in the building
你们想要谁
Who do you want?
蟹堡堡
Krabby
你们要他什么时候来
When do you want him?
现在
Now
蟹堡堡
Krabby
万岁
Hooray
小朋友们
Hey, kids
准备好见蟹堡堡小丑了吗
Are you ready to meet Krabby the Clown?
那好
All right
你们见吧
Here you go
小朋友们
Hey, kids
谢谢大家来捧场
Thank you all for coming
谢谢
Thank you
要吃超多的蟹黄堡哦
Eat plenty of Krabby Patties
老螃蟹  你又得手了
Krabs, you'd done it again
你确实得手了
I'll say you have
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你怎么能这样  蟹老板
How could you, Mr. Krabs?
你跟小朋友保证会有蟹堡堡小丑的
You promised these children Krabby the Clown
可我看到的却只有
But all I saw up there was
吝啬小气鬼
Cheapy the Cheapskate
我才不吝啬
I ain't cheap
趁番茄还没坏赶紧拿回厨房去
Now take this tomato
back to the kitchen before it spoils
可是夏天的真谛怎么办
But what about the true meaning of summer?
小朋友怎么办
What about the children?
小孩子
The children?
我才不稀罕什么小孩子
I don't care about the children
我只稀罕他们家长的钱
I just care about their parents' money
反正他们头脑简单  非常好骗
The fact that their feeble minds
are easily manipulated
拿便宜游乐场跟无能小丑都唬得住
by cheap playgrounds and talentless clowns
我可一点也不心疼
is no skin off my nose
适者生存  海绵宝宝
Survival of the fittest, SpongeBob
适者生存
Survival of the fittest
小朋友们
Hey, kids
蟹叔叔现在得去银行了
Uncle Krabs has to go to the bank now
抓住他
Get him
我估计没办法知道夏天的真谛了
I suppose I'll never know the true meaning of summer
原本可能知道过一次
I thought I knew it once
却已经很久远了
but that was a long, long time ago
你说的是今天早上吗
You mean this morning?
对啊
Yeah
快出来一下  海绵宝宝
Come outside, Mr. Squarepants
是夏天的奇迹
It's a summer miracle
万岁
Hoorah
好几千块的钱在随风飘
Thousands of dollars fluttering in the breeze
这应该就是夏天的真谛了
I guess that's the true meaning of summer
蟹老板哪去了
Where's Mr. Krabs?
他要错过夏天的乐趣了
He's missing out on all the summer fun
放我走吧
Let me go
我得拿走那些绿绿的东西
I got to get some of that green stuff
不对
No
不是那个绿绿的东西
Not that green stuff
不要
No
利马豆
露营
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
周末可终于到了
Finally, the weekend is here
这可不是以前的那种周末
and this isn't just any old weekend
海绵宝宝去露营
是海绵宝宝和派大星去露营的周末
This is the weekend SpongeBob and Patrick go camping
他们在树林迷路回不来  那有多好啊
Wouldn't it be great if they got lost in the woods
and never came back?
派大星  我好怕
Patrick, I'm scared
那可太好了
That would be great
等了好久就为了这一刻
You've waited a long time for this
软床
A soft bed
热茶
Warm tea
好书
A good book
还有整整两天没有
And two whole days with no
搞什么
What the?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你们两个不是应该在露营吗
aren't you two supposed to be camping?
我们本来就露营啊
We are camping
海绵宝宝  营地离家十尺远不算露营
SpongeBob, it's not camping
if you're ten feet from your house
地点不重要  户外就行了
It doesn't matter where you are
as long as you're outdoors
那些安逸的城里人
While all those soft city folk
还在安稳躺床上看书的时候呢
are safe in their beds reading books
我们置身此地  挑战自我
we're out here pitting ourselves
对抗着大自然那强大的力量
against the formidable forces of nature
要一起来吗
You want to join us?
不要
No
好吧
Okay
家里面要开心点
Have fun inside
家里面要开心点是几个意思
What do you mean, have fun inside?
就只是
Just
家里面开心点
have fun inside
明天见了
See you tomorrow
再见
Bye
你们这些小混蛋
You little sneak
看出来你们居心何在了
I see what you're doing
什么
What?
别以为我看不出来你们想干嘛
Don't think I can't see what you're doing
干嘛
What?
你们暗示我受不住这苦
You're saying I can't take it
可是我
But all I
你们说我娇生惯养
You're saying I'm soft
以为用家里面开心点这句话来唬我
You think your little "have fun inside" challenge
就能激我跟你们一起来露营
is going to make me come camping with you
根本就是不可能的事
but that is never going to happen
我决不可能整晚都坐这外面
There's no way I'm going to sit out here all night
陪着你们两个废物
with you two losers
给我死心吧
So get used to it
那好吧
Okay
家里面要开心点
Have fun inside
够了
That's it
我加进去
I'm in
倒要给你们看看什么叫露营
I'll show you camping
章鱼哥要跟我们一起来露营了
Squidward's going to come camping with us
现在你们就要看到真正的
Now you'll see how a real
露营家是怎么做的
outdoorsman does it
好了
Here we are
我的遥控自动组装帐篷
My remote-controlled self-assembling tent
好好看好好学
Watch and learn
好棒啊  章鱼哥
That was great, Squidward
可是你要怎么进去
but how do you get inside?
对啊  看起来破破烂烂的
Yeah, it's all crushy-looking
都还没搭起来  你们这些白痴
It isn't put up yet, you idiots
个性化设计
Customization
天才
Genius
他在弄松地板
He's tenderizing the ground
这样啊
Of course
记下来  记下来
Write that down, write that down
看吧
Voila
不过又有什么能比得过躺在星空下呢
But what could compare to just
lying out under the stars?
干活干得我都饿了
Well, I worked up an appetite
胃口都跟户外一样广大了
as big as all outdoors
该吃点东西了
Time for a little grub
我看你们两个怕是要去煮
I suppose you two are going to stew up
树枝跟石头了  是不是
some twigs and rocks, right?
才不是  有更好的东西吃
No, we got something even better
棉花糖
Marshmallows
棉花王
就跟宇航员吃东西一个样
Just like the astronauts eat
派大星呼叫海绵宝宝
Patrick to SpongeBob
能收到我信号吗
Do you read me?
完毕
Over
海绵宝宝呼叫派大星
SpongeBob to Patrick
已收到
I read you
完毕
Over
派大星呼叫海绵宝宝
Patrick to SpongeBob
我喜欢传话
I like going
完毕
Over
海绵宝宝呼叫派大星
SpongeBob to Patrick
我也喜欢
Me, too
海绵宝宝呼叫派大星  随便吃点吧
SpongeBob to Patrick, help yourself
完毕
Over
好吃
Yummy
派大星呼叫海绵宝宝
Patrick to SpongeBob
美味已着陆
The deliciousness has landed
你们两个宇航员吃棉花糖去吧
Well, you two astronauts can eat marshmallows
我可要吃一罐瑞典藤壶肉丸了
I'm going to have a can of Swedish barnacle balls
瑞典藤壶肉丸
去拿开罐器再来吃
just as soon as I can get my can opener
可是章鱼哥
But, Squidward
你走都走到这来了  还没带开罐器吗
didn't you take a can opener when you hiked out here?
凭什么这么麻烦
Why would I bother?
这里才离我家十尺远
We're ten feet from my house
可这里是荒野
But this is the wilderness
都不符合露营的精神了
It just doesn't seem to fit the camping spirit
太废了
Pretty weenie
好吧好吧
All right, all right
给我棉花糖
Give me a marshmallow
除了把融化的食物朝我吐之外
Okay, besides spitting molten foodstuffs at me
你们还做什么消遣的
what else do you do for fun?
那个嘛
Well
露营了长长一天之后呢
after a long day of camping
唱首轻松的篝火歌放松放松还不错
it's nice to unwind with a nice, relaxing campfire song
我管这首叫篝火歌之歌
I call this one "The Campfire Song Song"
让我们围在篝火周围
Let's gather round the campfire
唱我们的篝火歌
And sing our campfire song
就是篝火的篝  篝火的火
Our C-A-M-P-F-I-R-E
唱歌的歌  之歌
S-O-N-G song
要是以为我们唱歌速度
And if you don't think that we can sing it
快不起来  那就错了
Faster, then you're wrong
不过真想唱得快  可以跟着一起唱
But it'll help if you just sing along
篝火的篝  篝火的火
C-A-M-P-F-I-R-E
唱歌的歌  之歌
S-O-N-G song
篝火的篝  篝火的火
C-A-M-P-F-I-R-E
唱歌的歌  之歌
S-O-N-G song
要是以为我们
And if you don't think that we
唱歌速度快不起来  那就错了
Can sing it faster, then you are wrong
不过真想唱得快  可以跟着一起唱
But it'll help if you just sing along
篝火歌之歌
篝火的篝  篝火的火
C-A-M-P-F-I-R-E
唱歌的歌  之歌
S-O-N-G song
派大星
Patrick
之歌
Song
篝火的篝  篝火的火
C-A-M-P-F-I-R-E
章鱼哥
Squidward
好
Good
真想唱得快
It'll help
可以跟着一起唱
If you just sing along
好啊
Oh, yeah
刚刚是不是很放松啊
Now, wasn't that relaxing?
松个头
No
这才叫放松
Thisis relaxing
不好
Oh, no
我来救你  章鱼哥
I'll save you, Squidward
章鱼哥  你没事吧
Squidward, are you all right?
就这样
That's it
嚼
Chew
吞掉
and swallow
好了
There
舒服了没
Better?
这哪舒服
我本来还好好的  结果你射过来
I was just fine until you launched
那么个垃圾食物子弹  卡到我气管里
that ballistic junk food into my windpipe
可我必须得那样
But I had to
在这野外  竖笛吹得烂会很危险
It's too dangerous to play the clarinet badly
out here in the wilderness
可能会招来
It might attract
海熊
a sea bear
A sea bear?
你说的是不是那种
You mean like the ones that
不存在的玩意
don't exist?
你在讲什么
What are you saying?
根本就没那种东西
There's no such thing
就只是虚构的
They're just a myth
不对  章鱼哥
Oh, no, Squidward
海熊都很真实的
Sea bears are all too real
裤头村调查者就这么写的
It says so in the Bikini Bottom Inquirer
裤头村调查者
我跟海熊结婚了
"I married a Sea Bear"?
对啊  还有伪科学月刊
Yeah, and Fake Science Monthly
伪科学月刊
海熊跟童话
是真的
海熊跟童话是真的
"Sea Bears and Fairytales Are Real"?
这可是我听过最傻的玩意了
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard
可能是傻没错
Well, maybe it is stupid
但是也还笨
but it's also dumb
派大星说得对  章鱼哥
Patrick's right, Squidward
海熊的事可不是闹着玩的
Sea Bears are no laughing matter
我从前认识了这个人
Why, once I met this guy who knew this guy
认识的这个人认识的这个人
who knew this guy who knew this guy
认识的这个人的表亲
who knew this guy's cousin
你说得对
You're right
我应该要更小心一点
I should be more careful
其实啊  要不你们说说看
In fact, why don't you tell me
我不应该做什么事情
all of the things I shouldn't do
这样才不会招来海熊
if I want to keep the sea bears away
好  简单
Okay, that's easy
首先不要吹竖笛
First off, don't play the clarinet
好  然后呢
Okay, then what?
不要特别快地来回晃手电筒
Never wave your flashlight back and forth really fast
手电筒是它们的猎物
Flashlights are their natural prey
开玩笑吧
You're kidding
不要乱跺脚
Don't stomp around
会被当作挑衅
They take that as a challenge
对
Yeah
继续
Go on
不要吃奶酪
Don't ever eat cheese
切片的还是成块的
Sliced or cubed?
成块
Cubed
切片的没事
Sliced is fine
好好
Yeah, yeah
然后呢
And?
不要戴宽边帽
Never wear a sombrero
戴成傻子那样
in a goofy fashion
不要穿小丑鞋
Or clown shoes
不要穿圈环裙
Or a hoop skirt
还有千万
And never
不要
Ever
像黑猩猩那样尖叫
Screech like a chimpanzee
好多东西可以引来海熊  太强了吧
It's amazing how many things can set a sea bear off
海熊特可怕
They're horrible
而且
And
而且我突然感觉我们都有危险了
and suddenly, I have the sense we're all in danger
为什么
Why?
不知道
I don't know
感觉而已
Just a feeling
别这样
No
就这样
Yes
别这样
No
章鱼哥  别这样
Squidward, please don't
海绵宝宝  要怎么办
SpongeBob, what are we going to do?
肯定会有海熊来吃我们
A sea bear is sure to come and eat us
别担心  派大星
Don't worry, Patrick
我来在土里画个防海熊圈
I'll draw us an anti-sea bear circle in the dirt
好办法
Good thinking
所有专家都说
All the experts say
伪科学月刊
如何防海熊
独家
这是防御海熊攻击的唯一办法
it's the only defense against a sea bear attack
你们实在太好骗了
You guys are so gullible
看见没
See?
能引来海熊的所有事我都做了
I did everything that attracts a sea bear
结果什么都没发生
and nothing happened
要是真的有海熊  怎么一只都没出现
If sea bears really exist, why didn't one show up?
可能是因为
Maybe it's because
你没把宽边帽戴成傻子那样
you're not wearing your sombrero in a goofy fashion
对不起啊
Sorry
我可真傻
How silly of me
你是说要这样子吗
You mean like this?
不是
No
要那样子
Like that
章鱼哥  你没事吧
Squidward, are you okay?
有事
No
快点
Quick
趁海熊没回来跳进防海熊圈里来
Jump inside our anti-sea bear circle
before he comes back
对啊
Yeah
海熊的攻击经常不止一次
Sea bears often attack more than once
你们疯了吗
Are you crazy?
土里画的圈才防不住那种怪物
A dirt circle won't stop that monster
我要逃命去了
I'm running for my life
不要
No
不要跑
Don't run
海熊不喜欢那样子
Sea bears hate that
多谢提醒
Thanks for the tip
我看我得瘸着走回家了
I guess I'll just limp home, then
不要
No
海熊比起跑来更讨厌瘸
They hate limping more than running
那好吧  我看我得
Well, I guess I'll just have
刚刚忘了警告你不能爬
I should have warned you about crawling
我这回又干什么了
What did I do that time?
不清楚
I don't know
应该是它不喜欢你
I guess he just doesn't like you
假装成别的什么人
Pretend to be somebody else
给  画个圈
Here, draw a circle
好
Okay
那个是椭圆
That was an oval
得是圈才行
It has to be a circle
让开
Move over
有用
It worked
你们救了我的命
You guys saved my life
万岁
Hooray
对啊
Yeah
真高兴只是海熊而已
I'm glad it was just a sea bear
这个圈可挡不了海犀牛
This circle would never hold back a sea rhinoceros
什么东西会引来海犀牛
What attracts them?
海熊攻击的声音
The sound of a sea bear attack
幸好我们三个都穿着
Good thing we're all wearing
防海犀牛内衣
our anti-sea rhinoceros undergarments
对吧  章鱼哥
Right, Squidward?